

# João Dias web developer

github.com/joaotmdias linkedin.com/joaotmdias twitter.com/joaotmdias



I create great, accessible and rich web experiences for everyone. I've been fortunate enough to have been doing that since 2011.

Besides working as a Senior Front-end Engineer and web accessibility advocate, I also teach web development classes on the Polythecnic Institute of Coimbra. (ISEC)

On my free time I usually go out and explore the fantastic world of craft beers, rock out to some great live music and hit the gym whenever I can.

Experience

#### **ISEC**

Assistant Teacher 2022 - Today

#### Feedzai

Senior Front-end Engineer 2019 - Today

#### **WIT Software**

UI and Graphic Designer Frontend developer 2013 - 2019

## **Load Interactive**

Web and UI Designer 2011 - 2013

## joaodias.me

Web Designer 2009 - 20113

Teaching Javascript and React to first and second year students of Computer Science and Engineering

Front-end web development, design systems, software testing, mentoring and coaching.

Main focus on interface design as well as front-end web development. Also did a bit of graphics and motion design projects.

The do-it-all-designer at a mobile development startup. Did a bit of iOS coding as well.

Early years as a professional freelance web designer.

Skills

#### Development

HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, React, React Native, Node, Vue, Redux, Web components, Jest, Testing Library, Enzyme, Cypress, Web accessibility, WAI-ARIA, WCAG, Gatsby, Netx, jQuery, Git

## **Design and Visuals**

Figma, Sketch, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Affinity Publisher, Adobe InDesign, Adobe Premiere, Adobe After Effects, User Research and Usability

#### Others

Team leading, Project management, coaching and lecturing.

Education

## **ESEC**

Coimbra, Portugal Class of 2011

## **ESEC**

Coimbra, Portugal 2007-2008

# Bernardino Machado High School

Figueira da Foz, Portugal 2007 Degree in Communication and Multimedia Design.

1st year in Organizational Communication

Did my high-school graduation in Computers and Informatics.

Publications and public speaking

## ShiftAppens 2022

End-to-End testing with Cypress Coimbra, Portugal

# Now What? 2022

Building your first React app University of Coimbra, Portugal

## **OSDOC 2011**

EOS: Operating System for Students Lisboa, Portugal

## ResearchGate

Open source Operating System for students: EOS Project